Wh-What the...?
What was that?
Thunder maybe?
A Thunder Spear.
But why?
Let's head in that direction.
It's... It's so quiet.
Am I dying?
"The day will soon come when we sit at
the same table once again."
Has it not happened
exactly as I said it would?
Commander Pyxis?
Please let me thank you
for taking such swift action.
Not only have you forbidden
your troops from resisting us,
but in accordance with our demands,
you've also assembled every soldier
you have right here in Shiganshina.
Considering the trick you pulled
with the spinal fluid,
we didn't have much of a choice.
Zeke could turn us into
Titans at any moment.
And Shiganshina's been evacuated,
so it's the only safe place for us to be.
In any case.
What else could I do,
with so many old comrades
pointing guns at my back?
Please forgive me, Commander Pyxis.
My son drank the wine, too.
I'm doing this to protect him.
When did you first betray us?
You've no obligation to answer that.
I'm sorry.
I only ask because the time
at which you changed sides
seems to affect your
standing in this new regime.
Betray us early and you're
rewarded with a white armband.
It marks you as a proud
Jaegerist, correct?
Red armbands are used to
mark those who were
coerced into aiding the Jaegerists,
after learning they
had drunk tainted wine.
And finally.
These black armbands mark the
rest of us as ignorant fools
who drank the wine without
suspecting something was amiss.
I can't help but be reminded of Marley.
They employed a similar system when they
took over your homelands, did they not?
There's much to be
learned from our enemies.
Including how to make more, I see.
We offered to stand beside you as allies,
and you responded by
having us imprisoned.
That may be, but since it turns out that
the guests we refused to trust
were serving us tainted wine all along,
I don't know if moving against
you was foolish or wise.
Your actions were both foolish and wise.
I'd imagine that if you'd put your faith
in us and Zeke from the start,
the world could've already
been saved by now.
Hm?
You say that "the world"
could've been saved?
I was under the impression your plan was
to unite Zeke and Eren
so that they can trigger
a small-scale Rumbling
in order to deter the nations
of the world from attacking us
for the next 50 years or so.
But that plan would only
save this island, right?
Uh, Yelena?
It's too late at this point.
Zeke gave you all the time
you should've needed.
And what did you do with that time?
You plotted to repay
his mercy by killing him.
Zeke is the god who is
fated to save this world.
And you have invited his wrath.
So what?
Is there nothing we can do
but sit here and wait
for things to play out?
Here. You like tea?
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, Armin.
Do you think you could bust us
out of here by turning Titan?
'Fraid not. I'd blow up
half the town if I tried.
The Colossal Titan is powerful,
but it's far from precise.
Unlike Eren's Titan.
So. How did Eren end up
beating you to a pulp, Armin?
I think it's about time you told us.
Eren was hurting Mikasa with his words.
So I hit him and he responded in kind.
Huh?
Wait, what do you mean, "he was
hurting her"? What'd he say?
- -Well he...
- -Stop.
It's fine.
No. It isn't fine.
Seriously, tell me what he said to you.
May as well just let it go, Jean.
We already knew that he'd turned
into an absolute piece of shit.
But now he's lost his mind so completely,
that he went out of his way to hurt
the two people he used
to care about most.
Assuming he hasn't just lost it,
I don't see him doing that
without having some kind of reason.
I wonder.
Could he have some sort of hidden motive?
Heroes of Shiganshina.
It's always an honor to see you.
It pains me that our reunion
must take place across these bars.
No way. You're on their
side, too? Let us out!
Seems like more than you
have the right to ask for,
considering how you guys
kept me as a prisoner.
Just sit here and wait.
Zeke and Eren will meet soon.
Why, you.
You must be proud, Yelena.
It seems like everything's happening
exactly as you planned.
First, you get Eren
dancing to Zeke's tune.
Then, the raid on Marley
won you the Eldian people's support.
Which gave you free reign
to use your poisoned wine
to take over the military.
Eldia's yours.
As is the Founding Titan.
Now, you can crush Marley
and avenge your homelands.
That's it, right?
The real reason that you
volunteers came to this island?
We brought your country out of the past.
When we got here, this island
was downright primitive.
Huh?
But you were really just setting
it up for yourselves, right?
Making sure the place was worth ruling.
You were played for fools and defeated.
What else is there to be said?
Hey, Griez. Did you
seriously betray us
just so that Yelena would
make you one of her lackeys?
You little rat.
Are you stupid? I didn't take
the side of these devils.
You did.
You're the real traitor.
Say what?
You fell for some filth-blooded,
potato-grubbing devil,
just because she liked your food.
Get over here. I'll kill you!
Stop, Nicolo! Calm down!
The way you would blather about her
day and night was sickening.
Can't believe I was
stupid enough to think that
you'd get a grip once that bitch died.
What did you just call her?
I'll make it easy to understand.
That spawn-of-the-devil
whore deserved ex...
Yelena?
I apologize for his rudeness.
This island no longer
has any need for those
who would curse you as devils.
Please believe me when I tell you
that the goal we've been working towards
is not so petty or hollow
as taking revenge on Marley.
It is to sever the chains
of hate from this world,
and in doing so, to save
both Eldia and Marley.
We're done with secrets.
It's high-time you learned the truth.
Let me lay out the plan
that will save the world.
Zeke's so-called "euthanization" plan.
They're all vicious devils.
So, why haven't they killed me yet?
Brat who killed Sasha,
you're coming with me.
Huh? What do you want?
If you're hoping to
save Falco, you'll help me.
H-Help you? How?
You'll put out a distress
call on the radio
to lure out any spies
who've infiltrated the walls.
Don't move. Gabi. Stay quiet.
Pieck, you...!
I said quiet.
Now then.
Just to be doubly sure.
It's Eren Jaeger, correct?
Gabi. Take that rifle
and point it at Eren.
Gabi.
Eren. Move your hands
from your pockets.
And what'll you do if I don't?
I'll fire this pistol.
And then you'll be dead.
Brains on the floor.
Ever seen that?
You won't have time to transform.
Okay. So why
haven't you shot me?
If you aren't here to pull that trigger,
then what did you come here to do?
What'll happen if I keep
my hands in my pockets?
Doesn't seem like that's something
you'll ever get to know,
seeing as your brains will be on the fl...
I do know.
You aren't gonna shoot.
Because you weren't given permission
to kill the Founding Titan.
You've been told to
retrieve it, no matter what.
But in order to do that, you'd
need to get me to stay still
while you transformed into
a Titan and ate me alive.
That right?
What do I do?
Stand down.
Take your finger off the trigger, Gabi.
Huh?
If you were to defy your
orders by shooting me,
you wouldn't pay the price alone.
Your family in the zone
would pay it with you.
Yeah, you're right.
I won't shoot you.
And it doesn't look like I'm likely to
get a chance to eat you,
either. So that's that.
Seriously?
You found my Titan's footprints
from when I first snuck
onto the island, right?
I still think I did all right.
This was a hell of a time
to try and infiltrate
your military without
getting thrown in jail.
But I actually have another
reason not to shoot you.
If you can use the
Founding Titan's power,
then you have the strength
to defeat Marley, don't you?
You made the world your enemy.
You wouldn't have
done that unless you knew
you had a chance of winning, right?
What do you know that I don't?
Do you have more than just the Founder?
Hold on, Pieck.
What are you doing?
Gabi. You can put
the rifle down now.
Suppose I did.
What is it that you want?
Freedom for all Eldians.
And an end to their subjugation by Marley
and the rest of the world.
Also. I want to get my family
out of the internment zone.
I became a Warrior to help my father,
the one person I can call family,
get proper medical care.
He got the treatment
he needed and survived,
but knowing that my term
will be over soon,
he's been inconsolable.
Before I die and leave him on his own,
I want to show him that
Eldia has a bright future.
And for that to happen,
Marley's great empire
needs to be crushed.
There's nothing I won't
do toward that end.
So long as we can
slaughter all the Marleyans.
I'll help you however I can.
First I found out that Zeke
planned the attack on Liberio.
And now... Now you?
I thought we were trying to show
the world we're good Eldians!
If we just work hard and prove that,
then one day, we'll be set free!
Tell me. What have we been
fighting for if not that?
You're the same as Zeke...
A worthless traitor!
Let me ask you.
What are we?
Are we Marleyan? Or Eldian?
Which one comes first?
We're Marleyans first.
Honorary Marleyans.
Not so. Above all else,
we're Subjects of Ymir.
That's one truth which
we can never escape.
No matter what we call ourselves,
we're a people who can
turn or be turned into Titans.
But as both of us saw at Fort Slava.
The power of Titans is on
its way out as we speak.
Once it becomes obsolete,
the Marleyans will have no use for us.
They'll slaughter us
without a second thought!
It doesn't matter how hard we work
to try and prove that
we're "good" Eldians.
They will put us down like animals
before they ever set us free.
We have to secure our right
to live with our own hands,
even it means getting them dirty.
I need proof.
If you honestly intend
to cooperate with us,
then back up your words with action.
I'll show you where to find the soldiers
who snuck into town with me.
Wha...?
How exactly?
If you take me up to
the roof of this building,
I can point them out for you.
Fine.
They'll change our bodies
so we stop having children?
Correct.
That is the heart of
Zeke's euthanization plan.
Once the Founder's power
has done all its work,
all suffering related to Titans
will slowly come to an end.
You'll fade away. Peacefully.
Wait. How is that
gonna be peaceful?
If the population of Eldians withers
until we've all died out,
then in this country's final years,
it'll be nothing but old geezers.
How can we be sure we
won't get massacred then?
You think the world's
just gonna leave us alone?
The Rumbling can remain as a deterrent,
as long as your people retain
control of the Founder,
whilst ensuring that the royal
bloodline doesn't die out.
Fortunately, it seems Queen Historia
has already been blessed with an heir.
So, assuming her child lives a long life,
you just need to pass on
the Founder every 13 years.
You talk as if that's
an absolute certainty,
but it isn't.
"Certainties." "Sure things."
They aren't real.
Our world is full of risk and doubt.
There isn't a nation
in it that doesn't have
its share of troubles.
If there's one thing that is certain,
it's that this era of tears
and bloodshed is almost over.
The age of Titans will soon be
put to an end by Zeke and Eren.
There may be countless millennia
of human history that've yet to pass,
but even given that much time,
will anyone ever
accomplish an equal feat?
The Jaeger Brothers will be spoken of as
legendary symbols for
thousands of years to come.
Just as we speak today of ancient gods.
Long after they're dead,
they'll shine in mankind's memory.
They'll be known as
saviors who lit a path...
Is something the matter?
No. But to think that
your cause was so noble.
It just touched my heart!
That's wonderful to hear.
I'm so glad that you're
able to understand.
Bad news, Yelena!
We need you to come quick, please!
We're being invaded!
The enemy's arrived!
I hear someone was killed!
Apparently, the Cart Titan is here!
Seriously?
Yeah! Did she betray Marley?
That's what Jaeger said.
That's odd. What's all
the commotion about?
So is it safe to say that you've decided
to let us defect to your side?
If you actually give up
the other infiltrators.
Until you do, I'm keeping you
cuffed to the kid.
If you try to turn into a Titan,
she'll be burned to ash.
That's understandable.
And don't worry, the kid'll
come around soon enough.
That dainty thing is a Marleyan soldier?
Think we can trust her?
Hello, everyone!
Uh, hey. What did you
do with Falco?
He's around here, too.
But it seems he drank
some of Zeke's spinal fluid.
How'd it happen?
Who knows?
All I heard was that the dosed
wine got in his mouth somehow.
Did it happen when I...?
What's wrong?
This is completely
my fault. Again.
I see now.
You took over the military
by way of Zeke's spinal fluid.
Do you have any idea why he
possesses such a unique ability?
None at all. I don't
suppose you would know.
'Course not.
Only one person knows.
And that's Zeke himself.
Ever since I met him,
it's felt as though every word
that came out of his mouth was a lie.
Four years ago, I confirmed that hunch.
When I finally heard him
speak sincerely, to you.
"Believe me, Eren. I get it.
I know how you feel.
Someday, I'll come back
and save you from this."
If he wouldn't lie to you,
then surely he would've
told you the secret of his special power.
At the very least,
I assume he's told you
that it's connected
to drawing out the power
of the Founding Titan.
Hey there.
Why'd you go and shave your beard?
I thought it suited you.
Eren. That woman
is exceedingly dangerous.
It isn't safe to trust her.
I know. And I don't trust her
any more than she trusts me.
So. Why haven't you used
the Founder's power yet?
Where's Zeke?
You'll find that out soon enough.
Now show me. Where is the enemy?
Right there.
What the hell?
I think it's beginning.
The Titans have started to move.
Is that you, Galliard?
Didn't quite get him,
but it was worth a shot.
Wait, Pieck! You're not
actually a traitor?
Gabi! You really thought
I'd sell out my comrades?
Well, you said if we kept
fighting for Marley,
- -we'd end up getting put down!
- -Look up there.
I don't trust Marley one bit.
Having said that, I trust the comrades
who've fought at my side completely.
There's the smoke signal.
Pieck and Galliard tracked him down
and forced him out into the open.
The Founder is here.
Let's pay him back for Liberio!
I want that bastard dead!
Bring it on, then.
Reiner!